

MUKESH SELVARAJ

vs.mukesh@hotmail.com +91 9884966430





More than **8 years** of total experience in the information technology (IT) industry with excellent programming and database skills using agile methodologies. Providing **systems/Application** programming, analysis, and database designing, coding, performance tuning, testing and integration services. Qualified to play an integral role in the field of information technology where talents and experience will contribute to the use of technology in achieving company goals.

Certifications:

- F772-7442: Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer: Web Applications
- F748-1928: Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate: SQL Server 212/2014
- F707-1451: Microsoft Specialist
- **F679-2710:** Microsoft Certified Professional

Certification Exams:

- **70-486:** Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications.
- **70-480:** Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3.
- **70-487:** Developing Microsoft Azure and Web Services.
- **70-461:** Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012/2014.
- **70-462:** Administering Microsoft SQL Server 2012/2014 Databases.
- **70-463:** Implementing a Data Warehouse with Microsoft SQL 2012/2014.

Education:

• **B.E.** In **Electronics and Communication Engineering** From Anna University, India

Experience In:

C#, ASP.Net MVC, SQL Server 2014/2012, JavaScript, Jquery, HTML5, CSS3, Angular 4/2, Ecmascript 2016/2017, Typescript 2.0, WebPack, SystemJS, NodeJS, NPM, Angular CLI, JSPM, React, Aurelia, RedUX, ngRX/Store, React/Flux, ReactiveX/RxJS, Promises / A+ Async, Observables 2017, Saas, LeSS, Stylus, Google Material Design, Gulp, Grunt, Mocha, Jasmine, Karma, Angular Mobile, React Native, Ionic, NativeScript, Augury, Batarang, i18n, Web Workers, Service Workers, Kendo UI, Syncfusion, Google Analytics, Performance API, Codelyzer, tsLint, ng2Lint, Universal Electron, WPF, Azure, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio 2015/2013/2012, TFS, GitHub.

Experience Details:

Bank of America May 2013 – Till Date

.NET Developer

Managed the development of multiple enterprise wide .NET projects at BA. Worked on **ExceptionWeb** and **ACRT** (Annual Client Review Tool).

ExceptionWeb & ACRT: This application helps guide and educate the relevant personnel to make informed decisions on market trends and trading allowing their customers, in turn, to make informed decisions which is used by Bank of America employees internally. This project is an Enterprise-strength large-scale web application where emphasis was given to efficient memory management, scalability and high availability. I played a significant role in planning and implementing this.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in complete System Development Life Cycle (SDLC) stages as requirement gathering & analysis, technical Documentation, Modeling and design, Execution (development), integration and testing.
- I was also responsible for making this application for easy integration with other legacy apps. The other applications were able to reuse the custom built JQuery plugins in this application and exchange data between the two. I also used JSLint and CSSLint to assure coding best practices are followed in client code and style sheets.
- I also participated in the SOA design creating WCF Services and developing the Service Contracts, Operation Contracts etc. for enabling client applications to consume these services in a secure and efficient manner. I also implemented best practices and design patterns in achieving a robust architecture.
- I used QUnit to test the JavaScript components in an isolated environment that can be reused at various stages of development. I also followed the Test-Driven-Development (TDD) methodology.
- The build and deployment process was automated with the help of Team Foundation Server and MSBuild etc. and I was involved in achieving this goal as well.
- Apart from development, I was also involved in the over-all architecture such as business analysis, collecting user stories, sitting in brain-storming meetings to collect information for functional and technical documentation.
- Design, Architect, develop, and document reusable components in the .Net platform.
- Followed the best practices and pattern using various design patterns in the project development.
- Used Microsoft best practices and pattern ; **Application Blocks**(Data Application Block, Error Handling and Logging)
- Ensures development processes, standards, architectural review, code reviews and testing plans occur to ensure on time high quality program releases.
- Design and code review to ensure that the desired technical goals/objectives are met.
- Identify technical issues and recommend resolutions, Recommend direction on assignments.
- Anticipates issues, plans and assigns the work to team members in order to ensure a balanced workload among team members.
- Lead the development team towards Enterprise approach, i.e., open systems.
- Conduct review meetings and provide input to diverse teams and coordinate.

Environment: .NET 4.5, MVC 3/4, WCF, Kendo UI, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design, AJAX, JavaScript, JQuery, QUnit, AngularJS, UnderscoreJS, Mobile UI, SPA, JQGrid, Kendo UI, Telerik Reporting

Merrill Corporation

July 2011 – May 2013

.NET Developer

Managed the development of enterprise wide .NET project at Merrill. Worked on Merrill One (M1)

Responsibilities:

- Gathered required information with regular meetings with BAs, Architects to collect about the application components and procedures that are needed to start building the UI. Discussed the various requirements and made change requests depending upon the provided data from various sources.
- Responsibilities was to convert a legacy Windows based program to a web based enterprise application using .NET, C#, MVC, WCF, AJAX, JavaScript, JQuery, Mobile UI, Oracle, BizTalk as well as some third party tools such as Ext.NET, DevExpress etc.
- Involved in designing and analysis of the of various phases requirements analysis of the PD.
- Involved in creating User Interface screens from wireframe diagrams. Writing the server-side entry point code for the user interface. Consulted with the database team members and write WCF web services to persist and update data from the client.
- Developed Database Structure for pages including Tables, Stored Procedures and Indexing for Tuning and performance.
- Responsible included in creating reports in the application, with the tool DevExpress Reporting Engine.
- Involved in unit testing both the client scripts and the server code using tools such as Qunit and NUnit.
- Followed TDD (Test Driven Development) methodology which helped to write testable code more efficiently.
- Deployed to disparate servers as required by the project architects and PMs. Also responsible for deploying all these components.
- Responsible for fixing bugs reported by OA team.

- Coded for various controls (User, Custom and used third party) using ASP.NET, C#.NET.
- Unit tested and done integrated testing for the individual web pages and whole application.

Environment: .NET 4.0, MVC 3/4, WCF, Ext.NET 2.0, AJAX, JavaScript, JQuery, Mobile UI, Oracle

Kinship Technologies

.NET Developer

Managed the development of enterprise wide .NET project at Kinship. Worked on **ATRT** (**Analytical Test Request Tracking**)

May 2010 – July 2011

Responsibilities

- Worked with us in an "all-in-all" role for our pharmaceutical application development.
- Responsible from concept to delivery all by himself with meetings and discussion with the product stakeholders.
- Designed and architected a fully workflow based web application with the wireframes, mockups, and prototypes, proof of concepts etc.
- Designed User Interface screen which then generated a workflow to properly and securely propagate the flow to the next level user by notifying the user via emails and onscreen notification systems.
- Designed and developed all static and user configurable reports for the application.
- Used web services heavily for data manipulations and persistence. Implemented all necessary WCF services and deployed them for consumption.
- Involved in unit testing both the client scripts and the server code. Responsible for fixing bugs reported by QA team.

Environment: .NET 4.0, SQL Server 2005, MVC 2, Ext.NET 1.0, AJAX, JavaScript

Bapi Technologies June 2008 – April 2010

.NET Developer

Managed the development of enterprise wide .NET project at Bapi. Worked on **ConnectBeauty**

Responsibilities:

- Assisting development team to write functionality for the application under development.
- Writing components for the UI and for the business layer. Worked with .NET framework 2.0 and 3.5 and ASP.NET, Windows and Web
- Forms to fulfill the project requirements. Developed Web and Windows applications with the appropriate code.
- Writing Stored Procedures and Triggers using SQL Server 2008. And used Telerik and DevExpress (third party component suites)
- Developed components for all areas of the Software such as User Interface screens, the business logic code behind the screens, as well as the database interaction procedures required. With his Web application exposure.
- Designed and Developed Web Forms as User Interfaces, as well as the server side components to communicate with the Client interface.
- Developed a reusable and pluggable ecommerce engine that was used not only in the project he worked but also contributed to other projects.
- Involved in Unit Testing the entire application. He also acted as a liaison with the Quality Control team to make sure the application met all required standards.

Environment: .NET 3.5, SQL Server 2008, ASP.NET, AJAX, JavaScript, Devexpress

Declaration:

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned particulars are true & genuine and are as per the Certification.